<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/tag/announcements/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2020-08-26T23:48:59+00:00</updated>
  <id>/tag/announcements/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">SEA Lab | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Software Engineering and Analytics Laboratory</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
				<author>Arefin Sami</author>
        <author>
            <name>Arefin Sami</name>
          
          
        </author>
			
    
      
				<author>Tanzeem Bin Noor</author>
        <author>
            <name>Tanzeem Bin Noor</name>
          
          
        </author>
			
    
      
				<author>Josiane Kroll</author>
        <author>
            <name>Josiane Kroll</name>
          
          
        </author>
			
    
      
				<author>Shai Fridboim</author>
        <author>
            <name>Shai Fridboim</name>
          
          
        </author>
			
    
      
				<author>Vanessa Ramirez</author>
        <author>
            <name>Vanessa Ramirez</name>
          
          
        </author>
			
    
      
				<author>Mark Grushevski</author>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Grushevski</name>
          
          
        </author>
			
    
      
				<author>Jiaxing Mai</author>
        <author>
            <name>Jiaxing Mai</name>
          
          
        </author>
			
    
      
				<author>Zhihan Fang</author>
        <author>
            <name>Zhihan Fang</name>
          
          
        </author>
			
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">ASE 2020 Paper</title>
      <link href="/ASE" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ASE 2020 Paper" />
      <published>2020-07-30T08:30:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2020-07-30T08:30:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/ASE</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/ASE">&lt;p&gt;I am proud to announce that my latest paper, &lt;a href=&quot;/papers/2020-Hybrid.pdf&quot;&gt;Hybrid Deep Neural Networks to Infer State Models of Black-Box Systems&lt;/a&gt;, is accepted for publication at ACM/IEEE conference ASE ‘20.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that work, I created a deep neural network architecture to detect internal state of an autopilot system (developed by our industry partner, MicroPilot Inc), as a blackbox system. For more details, I encourage you to read the paper, available &lt;a href=&quot;/papers/2020-Hybrid.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. This is the first milestone of this project, later after submitting this paper I worked on replicating this paper on another case study as well as improving it on other aspects as well. 
The results of the next extensions can be read in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MJafarMashhadi/University-of-Calgary-Graduate-Thesis&quot;&gt;MSc thesis&lt;/a&gt;. Source code (incl. docs) and data are publicly available on Github as well. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sea-lab/hybrid-net&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MJafarMashhadi/pprz_tester&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the current devastating COVID situation, I will be presenting it online. Presentation slides and probably aa recording of the presentation will become available later, check &lt;a href=&quot;/publications/&quot;&gt;publications page&lt;/a&gt; on this website out for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Inferring behavior model of a running software system is quite useful for several automated software engineering tasks,
such as program comprehension, anomaly detection, and testing. Most existing dynamic model inference techniques are 
white-box, i.e., they require source code to be instrumented to get run-time traces. However, in many systems, 
instrumenting the entire source code is not possible (e.g. when using black-box third-party libraries) or might be very 
costly. Unfortunately, most black-box techniques that detect states over time are either univariate, or make assumptions 
on the data distribution, or have limited power for learning over a long period of past behavior. To overcome the above 
issues, in this paper, we propose a hybrid deep neural network that accepts as input a set of time series, one per 
input/output signal of the system, and applies a set of convolutional and recurrent layers to learn the non-linear 
correlations between signals and the patterns, over time. We have applied our approach on a real UAV auto-pilot solution 
from our industry partner with half a million lines of C code. We ran 888 random recent system-level test cases and 
inferred states, over time. Our comparison with several traditional time series change point detection techniques showed 
that our approach improves their performance by up to 102%, in terms of finding state change points, measured by F1 score. 
We also showed that our state classification algorithm provides on average 90.45% F1 score, which improves traditional 
classification algorithms by up to 17%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Mohammad Jafar Mashhadi</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="announcements" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">I am proud to announce that my latest paper, Hybrid Deep Neural Networks to Infer State Models of Black-Box Systems, is accepted for publication at ACM/IEEE conference ASE ‘20.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">On ASE 2019</title>
      <link href="/ASE-conference" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On ASE 2019" />
      <published>2019-11-08T16:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-11-08T16:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/ASE-conference</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/ASE-conference">&lt;p&gt;Our lab’s latest journal paper, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1905.02245.pdf&quot;&gt;Interactive Semi-automated SpecificationMining for Debugging: An Experience Report&lt;/a&gt;, is accepted to be presented at journal first conference second track of ASE conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that reserach project in close collaboration with our industry partner, we developed a novel debugging method using latest specification mining methods. The developers in the company found this method (and the tool developed along with it) a valuable asset and a useful asset in their toolbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am looking forward to see you all in the conference and have some chat about it.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Hadi Hemmati</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="announcements" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Our lab’s latest journal paper, Interactive Semi-automated SpecificationMining for Debugging: An Experience Report, is accepted to be presented at journal first conference second track of ASE conference.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">On ICSE 2019</title>
      <link href="/ICSE-conference" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On ICSE 2019" />
      <published>2019-04-16T16:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-04-16T16:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/ICSE-conference</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/ICSE-conference">&lt;p&gt;I am happy to announce that we are going to participate in ICSE 2019 in Montréal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our lab was very productive in 2018 year and we had two accepted papers in the conference (and co-located conferences), one student volunteer, and two students on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://2019.icse-conferences.org/track/icse-2019-Software-Engineering-Mentoring-Workshop&quot;&gt;mentorship workshop program&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Picture credit: Marc-Olivier Jodoin&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Hadi Hemmati</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="announcements" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">I am happy to announce that we are going to participate in ICSE 2019 in Montréal.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
